Guide to the Society for Slovene Studies Records, 1973-2012 SPEC.HRL.SSS
Ohio State University Libraries Special Collections
Timothy Pogacar (2007-2012) succeeded as president in 2007. Michael Biggins (University of Washington), having replaced Derbyshire as secretary in 2006 continued in that capacity; and Rogel remained treasurer until the end of Pogacar's two terms. The Society continued to participate in AAASS/ASEEES conferences with impressive numbers. In New Orleans (2007) they offered a record number (12) of panels, with only a few less in Philadelphia (2008), Boston (2009), and in Los Angeles (2010). This does not include SSS members who gave presentations in cross-cultural or interdisciplinary sessions. Increasing numbers of participants from abroad helped account for the escalating numbers. During the Milac presidency the Society also had begun working with other Central Europeanists toward broader collaborations. After 2008 six affiliate societies also initiated "networking" receptions. The Society, thanks to program coordinator Veronica Aplenc (University of Pennsylvania), was instrumental in securing a grant from the Slovene government for the first networking event. The year 2008 was the Society's 35th anniversary.
Accomplishments of the Pogacar presidency also included facilitating, with the aid of Michael Biggins and the University of Washington's Open Journal Systems, an online presence of digitized issues of Slovene Studies. The journal will also remain in print, and its editing will increasingly be performed online as well. Pogacar's hope was to draw new, younger members into administrative positions and also to pursue the Center goal. Regarding the latter some preliminary talks have taken place with The Ohio State University. The matter of a home for SSS archive has been resolved. Copies of Society publications, the papers of its presidents and other officials are now housed at the Ohio State University Library's Special Collections, administered by Predrag Matejic, curator of the Hilandar Research Library. The official documents began arriving in Columbus, Ohio, in summer 2010, and are currently being processed by M.A. Johnson, an archivist who studied South Slavic and Balkan languages under Kenneth E. Naylor (19937-1992; professor of South Slavic Linguistics, The Ohio State University). She is also a member of the Society for Slovene Studies.
Written by Carole Rogel, June 2012
Related Materials
The papers of the first president of the Society for Slovene Studies, Rado Lencek, are located in the Narodna in univerzitetna knjiznica (NUK) [National and University Library of Slovenia], in Ljubljana, Slovenia. These papers include materials and records related to the Society for Slovene Studies.
American Association for South Slavic Studies; American Association for the Advancement of Slavic Studies; American Scholars for an Independent Slovenia (ASIS); Bernik, France; Biggins, Michael; Cooper, Henry R.; Cox, John K., 1964-; Derbyshire, William W. (William Wadleigh), 1936-; Hocevar, Toussaint; Kapsch, Stefan; Lavrin, Janko, 1887-1986; Lencek, Rado L. (Rado Ludovik), 1921-2005; Matejic, Predrag; Mazek, Warren F., 1938-; Milac, Metod M., 1924-; Naylor, Kenneth E.; Necak, Dusan; Paternost, Joseph; Petric, Ernest; Pogacar, Timothy; Priestly, Tom; Rogel, Carole; Rupel, Dimitrij; Society for Slovene Studies; Stermole, David; Velikonja, Joseph
- Toussaint Hocevar, 1973-1983; Series 1
  - Unlabeled accordion file of financial records, 1981-1983 (Folder 1)
  - Soc. Slovene Studies Constitution, [1973-1983] (Folder 2)
  - Lencek, [1973-1983] (Folder 3)
  - Soc. for Slov. Studies Secretary's Business, 1974-1975 (Folder 4)
  - SSS Bibliography of members, [1973-1983] (Folder 5)
  - SSS Correspondence - Business (incl. inquires), [1973-1983] (Folder 6)
  - SSS Correspondence - Members, [1973-1983] (Folder 7)
  - SSS Financial records, 1975-1976 (Folder 8)
  - SSS Financial records, 1976-1977 (Folder 9)
  - SSS Financial records, 1977-1978 (Folder 10)
  - SSS Financial records, 1978-1979 (Folder 11)
  - SSS Financial records, 1979-1980 (Folder 12)
  - SSS Financial records, 1980-1981 (Folder 13)
  - SSS Financial records, 1981-1982 (Folder 14)
  - SSS Internal Revenue, [1973-1983] (Folder 15)
  - SSS Minutes - Business meetings, [1973-1983] (Folder 16)
  - SSS Letter - copies [first letter 6/1/1978 - eighth 7/15/1980], 1978-1980 (Folder 17)
  - SSS Letter - materials, 1978-1980 (Folder 18)
  - SSS Printing Fund, [1973-1983] (Folder 19)
  - SSS Sale of publications, [1973-1983] (Folder 20)
  - SSS Subscriptions, [1973-1983] (Folder 21)
  - Society for Slovene Studies: Various items and correspondence, [1973-1983] (Folder 22)
  - SSS - Various forms old, [1973-1983] (Folder 23)
- Carole Rogel, 1973-2012; Series 2
  - New York Conf. (April), 1973 (Folder 1)
  - Correspondence - Milwaukee Conf. (May), 1974 (Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 1975 (Folder 3)
  - AAASS/SSS Conference Atlanta (Oct), 1975 (Folder 4)
  - Correspondence MidWest Slavic Conf Chicago (May), 1976 (Folder 5)
  - Correspondence AAASS/SSS Conf St. Louis (Oct), 1976 (Folder 6)
  - Corresp + Conf. Ann Arbor (MidWest May) Washington (AAASS/SSS/Oct), 1977 (Folder 7)
  - Correspondence NY City Conf. Minor Slavic Lang; Nat'lities Papers, 1978 (Folder 8)
  - Corresp New Haven AAASS/SSS Conf. (Oct), 1979 (Folder 9)
  - Correspondence AAASS/SSS Kansas (Oct), 1983 (Folder 10)
  - Correspondence Rogel (President) SSS, 1984 (Folder 11)
  - Chicago (Mar) 400 Yrs of S. Slav Prot. Ref., 1984 (Folder 12)
  - AAASS/SSS New York (Nov), 1984 (Folder 13)
  - Correspondence Rogel (President), 1985 (Folder 14)
  - ICSEES/AAASS/SSS Conf. Washington (Oct 30-Nov 3) - Panels - Business, 1985 (Folder 15)
  - Correspondence Rogel (President), 1986 (Folder 16)
  - Conference AAASS/SSS New Orleans (Nov), 1986 (Folder 17)
  - Correspondence Rogel (President), 1987 (Folder 18)
  - Conference AAASS/SSS Boston (Nov), 1987 (Folder 19)
  - Correspondence Rogel (President), 1988 (Folder 20)
  - Conference (MidWest Slavic/SSS 15th Anniv.) Bloomington (March), 1988 (Folder 21)
  - Conference: BLED (May) Corresp: re Cooperation w. Slovene Academics (Necak, etc.), 1988 (Folder 22)
  - Conference (AAASS/SSS) Hawaii (Nov), 1988 (Folder 23)
  - Correspondence Rogel (President), 1989 (Folder 24)
  - Hocevar Festschrift, 1989 (Folder 25)
  - Conference AAASS/SSS Chicago (Nov), 1989 (Folder 26)
  - Correspondence Rogel (President), 1990 (Folder 27)
  - Conferences Harrogate ICSEES/SSS (July) Washington AAASS/SSS (Oct), 1990 (Folder 28)
  - A.S.I.S.1991 (labeled accordion file containing six folders - only one labeled) (Folder 29)
  - American Scholars for an Independent Slovenia: Records, 1991-1992 (Folder 30)
  - Corresp + Conf (AAASS/SSS) Miami (Nov), 1991 (Folder 31)
  - Correspondence Conference: Phoenix AAASS/SSS (Nov), 1992 (Folder 32)
  - Conferences: Hawaii (AAASS/SSS) Nov Toronto (ATSEEL) Dec., 1993 (Folder 33)
  - Correspondence (Rogel) Conference (AAA/SSS) Philadelphia (Nov), 1994 (Folder 34)
  - Correspondence (Rogel) Conference (AAASS/SSS) Washington (Oct), 1995 (Folder 35)
  - Correspondence/Rogel Conference AAASS/SSS Boston (Nov), 1996 (Folder 36)
  - Correspondence (Rogel) Conference: Seattle AAASS/SSS (Nov.), 1997 (Folder 37)
  - SSS Correspondence & Conferences Rogel, 1998 (Folder 38)
  - Accordion file labeled "1998/99 crisis and afternath", 1998-1999 (Folder 39)
  - Correspondence (Rogel) Conf.: Boca Raton AAASS/SSS - 25th anniv. (Sept.), 1998 (Folder 40)
  - Corresp./Rogel Conf: St. Louis AAASS/SSS (Nov), 1999 (Folder 41)
  - Corresp./Rogel Conf: Denver AAASS/SSS (Nov), 2000 (Folder 42)
  - Corresp./Rogel Conf: Crystal City AAASS/SSS (Nov), 2001 (Folder 43)
  - Corresp./Rogel Conf: Pittsburgh AAASS/SSS (Nov), 2002 (Folder 44)
  - Corresp./Rogel Conf: Toronto AAASS/SSS (Nov), 2003 (Folder 45)
  - Conference Boston (AAASS/SSS) (Dec), 2004 (Folder 46)
  - Corresp./Rogel Conf: Stalt Lake City AAASS/SSS (Nov), 2005 (Folder 47)
  - Corresp./Rogel Conf: Washington AAASS/SSS (Nov), 2006 (Folder 48)
  - Corresp./Rogel Conf: New Orleans AAASS/SSS (Nov), 2007 (Folder 49)
  - Corresp./Rogel Conf: Philadelphia AAASS/SSS (Nov), 2008 (Folder 50)
  - Corresp./Rogel Conf: Boston AAASS/SSS (Nov), 2009 (Folder 51)
- Henry R. Cooper, 1979-2001; Series 3
  - SS 6/1-2 Sales, [1979-2001] (Folder 1)
  - SSS Presidencey, 1990 (Folder 2)
  - SSS Finance Committee, [1979-2001] (Folder 3)
  - Slov. Studies 1:1, 1979 (Folder 4)
  - SSS - Ongoing Business, [1979-2001] (Folder 5)
  - S.S.S. Future Plans, [1979-2001] (Folder 6)
  - SSS - Documents, [1990-?] (Folder 7)
  - SSS, 2000 (Folder 8)
  - SSS, 2001 (Folder 9)
  - Society for Slovene Studies, 1997-? (Folder 10)
  - SSS Exec Commit Business Meeting, 1999 (Folder 11)
  - SSS, 1999 (Folder 12)
  - Slovene Studies Center, [1999-2001] (Folder 13)
  - S.S.S. Addresses + Mailing List, 1999 (Folder 14)
  - Book: Who's Who of Slovene descent in the United States, 1995 (Folder 15)
  - American-Slovene Congress, [1979-2001] (Folder 16)
  - American Scholars for an Independent Slovenia, Inc., 1990-? (Folder 17)
  - SSS General, [1979-2001] (Folder 18)
  - Society for Slovene Studies Miscellaneous, [1979-2001] (Folder 19)
  - SSS - Panels, [1990-1995] (Folder 20)
  - Slovene Studies, [1979-2001] (Folder 21)
- Tom Priestly, 1985-1998; Series 4
  - CD: SSS Archive, [1985-1998]
- John K. Cox, 1980-2008; Series 5
  - SSS Membership Lists, 1990-2007 (Folder 1)
  - S.S.S. - Membership Lists, 1980s (Folder 2)
  - SSS: Old Memberships rec'd from John Cox - accordion file, pre-1998 (Folder 3)
  - SSS - Treasurer's Records, Feb. 1996-Oct. 1999 (Folder 4)
  - Ballots Constitutional Amendments, 6/2008 (Folder 5)
- Metod Milac, 1979-2009; Series 6
  - SSS Program Coordinator, 1979-1984 (Folder 1)
  - Secretary, 1996-1999 (Folder 2)
  - SSS Center for Slovene Studies partial documentation, President, 2000-2006 (Folder 3)
  - President's papers, 2000-2006 (Folder 4)
  - President's papers - additions, 2000-2006 (Folder 5)
  - SSS Program Coordinator 1979-1984, Secretary 1996-1999, President 2000-2006, 1979-2006 (Folder 6)
  - Salt Lake City, 2005 (Folder 7)
  - SAZU Slovenska drustva, 2005 (Folder 8)
  - Suhadolnik, Alenda, Consul General, New York, 2005 (Folder 9)
  - Toronto, 2003 (Folder 10)
  - Velikonja, Joze, 2006 (Folder 11)
  - Vodopivec, Peter, 2006? (Folder 12)
  - SSS Washington [includes newspaper issue of Ameriska Domovina (2 Nov 2006) about conference in Washington] (Folder 13)
  - Zbogar, Samuel, Ambassador, 2005-? (Folder 14)
  - Zigon, Zvone, Consul General [includes newspaper issue of Ameriska Domovina (19 Apr 2007)] (Folder 15)
  - Pogacar, Tim, 2000-2006? (Folder 16)
  - SSS President, 2000-2006 (Folder 17)
  - Publicity, [2000-2006?] (Folder 18)
  - Reindl, Donald, [2000-2006?] (Folder 19)
  - Rogel, Carole, [2000-2006?] (Folder 20)
  - Ryavec, Karl W.; rusinow, Dennison, [2000-2006?] (Folder 21)
  - AAASS, [2000-2006?] (Folder 22)
  - Apenc, Veronica, [2000-2006?] (Folder 23)
  - Boston, 2009 (Folder 24)
  - Central Europe, [2000-2009?] (Folder 25)
  - Cooper, Henry R., [2000-2009?] (Folder 26)
  - Derdzinski, Joseph; Derbyshire, Bill, [2000-2009?] (Folder 27)
  - Golez, Marjetka, [2000-2009?] (Folder 28)
  - Kapsch, Stefan, [2000-2009?] (Folder 29)
  - Lemenc, Mari Arbo, [2000-2009?] (Folder 30)
  - Lencek, Rado [includes newspaper issue of Ameriska Domovina (24 Feb. 2005) with Lenchek obituary] (Folder 30)
  - New Orleans [includes newspaper clipping of Ameriska Domovina (7 Feb. 2008) with article about the conference] (Folder 31)
  - Philadelphia, 2008 (Folder 32)
  - Prinat-Greenberg, Marta, [2000-2009?] (Folder 33)
- Newsletters, No. 1-69. Recent issues available www.slovenestudies.com, 1973-2011; Series 7
- Publications, 1978-2011; Series 8
  - Susel, Rudolph M., ed. assisted by Toussaint Hocevar and Carole Rogel. Papers in Slovene Studies 1977. NY: Published by Society for Slovene Studies, 1978. (Volume 1)
  - Cooper, Henry R., Jr., ed. Papers in Slovene Studies 1978. NY: Published by Society for Slovene Studies, 1981. (Volume 2)
  - Slovene Studies: Journal of The Society for Slovene Studies 1.1, 1.2, 1979 (Volume 3)
  - Slovene Studies: Journal of The Society for Slovene Studies 2.1, 2.2, 1980 (Volume 4)
  - Slovene Studies: Journal of The Society for Slovene Studies 3.1, 3.2, 1981 (Volume 5)
  - Slovene Studies: Journal of The Society for Slovene Studies 4.1, 4.2, 1982 (Volume 6)
  - Slovene Studies: Journal of The Society for Slovene Studies 5.1, 5.2, 1983 (Volume 7)
  - Slovene Studies: Journal of The Society for Slovene Studies 6.1-2, 1984 (Volume 8)
  - Cooper, Henry R., Jr., ed. Four Hundred Years of the South Slavic Protestant Reformation, 1584-1984. Slovene Studies: Journal of The Society for Slovene Studies 7.1-2, 1985 (Volume 9)
  - Slovene Studies: Journal of The Society for Slovene Studies 7.1-.2, 1985 (Volume 10)
  - Slovene Studies: Journal of The Society for Slovene Studies 8.1. Problems of European Minorities: The Slovene Case. Special III World Congress Issue., 1986 (Volume 11)
  - Slovene Studies: Journal of The Society for Slovene Studies 8.2. Mary Molek Memorial Issue., 1986 (Volume 12)
  - Slovene Studies: Journal of The Society for Slovene Studies 9.1-2, 1987 (Volume 13)
  - Priestly, Tom M.S., Olga B. Nedeljkovic, and Henry R. Cooper, Jr., eds. Lubi Slovenci: A Festschrift to Honor Rado L. Lencek on the Occasion of his Sixty-First Birthday, 3 October 1986. Published as Slovene Studies: Journal of The Society for Slovene Studies 9.1-2, 1987 (Volume 14)
  - Slovene Studies: Journal of The Society for Slovene Studies 10.1, 10.2, 1988 (Volume 15)
  - Lokar, Ales, Warren F. Mazek, and Tom M.S. Priestly, ed. In Honor of the Memory of Toussaint S. Hocevar (1927-1987). Published as Slovene Studies: Journal of The Society for Slovene Studies 11.1-2, 1989 (Volume 16)
  - Slovene Studies: Journal of The Society for Slovene Studies 11.1-2, 1989 (Volume 17)
  - Slovene Studies: Journal of The Society for Slovene Studies 12.1, 12.2, 1990 (Volume 18)
  - Slovene Studies: Journal of The Society for Slovene Studies 13.1, 13.2, 1991 (Volume 19)
  - Slovene Studies: Journal of The Society for Slovene Studies 14.1, 14.2, 1992 (Volume 20)
  - Slovene Studies: Journal of The Society for Slovene Studies 15.1-2, 1993 (Volume 21)
  - Slovene Studies: Journal of The Society for Slovene Studies 16.1, 16.2 Note: Volume 16.1 contains the Cumulative Index with abstracts of Slovene Studies 1-15 and P apers in Slovene Studies 1975-1978, 1994 (Volume 22)
  - Slovene Studies: Journal of The Society for Slovene Studies 17.1-2, 1995 (Volume 23)
  - Slovene Studies: Journal of The Society for Slovene Studies 18.1, 18.2, 1996 (Volume 24)
  - Slovene Studies: Journal of The Society for Slovene Studies 19.1-2, 1997 (Volume 25)
  - Slovene Studies: Journal of The Society for Slovene Studies 20-21, 1998-1999 (Volume 26)
  - Slovene Studies: Journal of The Society for Slovene Studies 22.1-2, 2000 (Volume 27)
  - Slovene Studies: Journal of The Society for Slovene Studies 23.1-2, 2001 (Volume 28)
  - Slovene Studies: Journal of The Society for Slovene Studies 24.1-2, 2002 (Volume 29)
  - Slovene Studies: Journal of The Society for Slovene Studies 25.1-2, 2003 (Volume 30)
  - Slovene Studies: Journal of The Society for Slovene Studies 26.1-2, 2004 (Volume 31)
  - Slovene Studies: Journal of The Society for Slovene Studies 27.1-2, 2005 (Volume 32)
  - Slovene Studies: Journal of The Society for Slovene Studies 28.1-2, 2006 (Volume 33)
  - Slovene Studies: Journal of The Society for Slovene Studies 29.1-2, 2007 (Volume 34)
  - Slovene Studies: Journal of The Society for Slovene Studies 30.1, 30.2, 2008 (Volume 35)
  - Slovene Studies: Journal of The Society for Slovene Studies 31.1, 31.2, 2009 (Volume 37)
  - Slovene Studies: Journal of The Society for Slovene Studies 32.1-2, 2010 (Volume 38)
  - Slovene Studies: Journal of The Society for Slovene Studies 33.1, 33.2, 2011 (Volume 39)
  - Velikonja, Joseph, and Rado L. Lencek, comp. and eds. Who's Who of Slovene Descent in the United States: First Preliminary edition. Seattle-New York Research and Documentation Society for Slovene Studies Institute on East Central Europe, Columbia University and Department of Geography, University of Washington., 1992 (Volume 40)